# CURRICULUM VITÆ

# Guillem Domènech Fuertes

e-mail: domenechguillem@gmail.com webpage: https://domenechcosmo.netlify.app

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY: I am a research associate at the Institute for Theoretical Physics, Heidelberg university, working on gravity and cosmology. I have 24 published articles with more than 440 citations in total. My research topics are:

General Relativity; Early Universe Physics; Inflation; Modified Gravity; CMB Physics; Cosmological Perturbation Theory; Gravitational Waves; Euclidean Gravity; Dark Matter; Dark Energy.

### EDUCATION:

2014 - 2017 Doctor Course in Cosmology,

Yukawa Institute for Theoretical Physics, University of Kyoto, Japan

Thesis: "Inflationary Cosmology in Scalar-Tensor Theories"

Advisor: Prof. Misao Sasaki

2013 - 2014 Research student in Cosmology,

Yukawa Institute for Theoretical Physics, University of Kyoto, Japan

Advisor: Prof. Misao Sasaki

2012 - 2013 Master of Physics in Astrophysics, Particle Physics and Cosmology,

University of Barcelona, Spain

9.6/10 First Class Honours | Major: Cosmology and Particle Physics

Thesis: Canonical Halo Mass Definition and Universal Halo Mass Function

Advisor: Prof. Eduard Salvador-Solé

2008 - 2012 Bachelor in Physics

University of Barcelona, Spain

9.1/10 First Class Honours | Major: Particle Physics

ACADEMIC POSITIONS:

10/2020 - present Marie-Curie Fellini Fellow

Istituto Nazionale di Fisica Nucleare, Padova University, Italy

Host: Sabino Matarrese

10/2017 - 09/2020 Research Associate

Institute for Theoretical Physics, Heidelberg University, Germany

Host: Christof Wetterich

SUPERVISION OF GRADUATE STUDENTS:

04/2018 - 03/2019 Co-supervised master student (w/ Javier Rubio): Julius Wons.

Institute for Theoretical Physics, Heidelberg University, Germany Thesis: *Interacting spectator fields in the Primordial Universe*<sup>[P16]</sup>

Institutional responsibilities:

2018 - 2020 Seminar organiser of the cosmology group (Prof: Luca Amendola)

ITP, Heidelberg University

\_\_\_\_\_\_

### FELLOWSHIPS AND AWARDS:

- 2020 Marie-Curie Fellini Fellow (European Union's Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme No.754496 and Istituto Nazionale di Fisica Nucleare.
- 2020 Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) Postdoctoral Fellowship (declined)
- 2020 Participant of InvisiblesPlus programme, European Union's Horizon 2020 under the Marie Skłodowska-Curie grant agreement No.690575 (one month visit to Berkeley University)
- 2019 Balzan Center for Cosmological Studies Program (one month visit to Johns Hopkins University)
- 2014 Japanese Government Scholarship (MEXT) for Graduate Students (Doctor course)
- 2012 Faculty of Physics Masters Scholarship (Catalunya Caixa)
- 2008 Undergraduate degree Scholarship (Caixa Manresa)

## TEACHING ACTIVITIES:

04/2019 - 07/2019 Tutoring for Advanced Quantum Field Theory (Prof: Christof Wetterich)

ITP, Heidelberg University, Germany

10/2018 - 03/2019 Co-coordinator of the Cosmology course (Prof: Luca Amendola)

ITP, Heidelberg University, Germany

04/2018 - 07/2018 Co-coordinator of the General Relativity course (Prof: Luca Amendola)

ITP, Heidelberg University, Germany

10/2017 - 03/2018 Tutoring for Theoretical Statistical Physics (Prof: Ulrich Schwarz)

ITP, Heidelberg University, Germany

-----

### Refereeing experience:

- Journal of Cosmology and Astroparticle Physics: co-refereed 6 and refereed 12 papers.
- Physics of the Dark Universe: refereed 2 papers.
- International Journal of Modern Physics D: refereed 1 paper.
- European Physics Journal C: refereed 1 paper.

\_\_\_\_\_\_

#### CHAIRING EXPERIENCE:

• Chaired inflation session in Gravity and Cosmology 2018, February, YITP, Kyoto University, Japan.

-----

### **OUTREACH ACTIVITIES:**

02/2020 Outreach talk to bachelor students at University of San Marcos, Lima, Peru.

12/2015 Outreach talk in Sunion high-school, Barcelona, Spain.

05/2013 Outreach talk in Sunion high-school, Barcelona, Spain.

\_\_\_\_\_

## Computational Tools:

Boltzmann codes: CLASS (basic)
Monte Carlo codes: MontePython (basic)

Computer Languages: Python (intermediate) & Fortran (intermediate)

Scientific Software: Mathematica including xAct (tensor computation), LATEX & R

\_\_\_\_\_\_

### Languages:

Spanish: Native
Catalan: Native
English: Fluent
Japanese: Intermediate

\_\_\_\_\_\_

# LIST OF PUBLICATIONS

### **Peer Reviewed Publications**

- [P21] "Planck residuals anomaly as a fingerprint of alternative scenarios to inflation" Guillem Domènech, Xingang Chen, Abraham Loeb & Marc Kamionkowski. arXiv:2005.08998. JCAP10(2020)005
- [P20] "Induced gravitational waves as a probe of thermal history of the universe" Guillem Domènech, Shi Pi& Misao Sasaki. arXiv:2005.12314. JCAP 08 (2020) 017
- [P19] "Induced gravitational waves in a general cosmological background" Guillem Domènech. arXiv:1912.05583. IJMPD Vol. 29, No. 03, 2050028 (2020)
- [P18] "Could the black hole singularity be a field singularity?" Guillem Domènech, Atsushi Naruko, Misao Sasaki & Christof Wetterich. arXiv:1912.02845. IJMPD Vol. 29, No. 03, 2050026 (2020)
- [P17] "Lensing anomaly and oscillations in the primordial power spectrum" Guillem Domènech & Marc Kamionkowski arXiv:1905.04323. JCAP11 (2019) 040
- [P16] "Mimicking features in alternatives to inflation with interacting spectator fields" Guillem Domènech, Javier Rubio & Julius Wons, arXiv:1905.04323, Phys.Lett. B790 (2019) 263-269,
- [P15] "Gravitational waves from global cosmic strings in quintessential inflation" Dario Bettoni, Guillem Domènech & Javier Rubio, arXiv:1810.11117, JCAP 1902 (2019) 034,
- [P14] "Vacuum birefringence and the Schwinger effect in (3+1) de Sitter" Mariona Banyeres, Guillem Domènech & Jaume Garriga, arXiv:1809.08977, Phys.Lett. B790 (2019) 263-269,
- [P13] "Vector disformal transformation of generalized Proca theory" Guillem Domènech, Shinji Mukohyama, Ryo Namba & Vassilis Papadopoulos, arXiv:1807.06048, Phys.Rev. D98 (2018) no.6, 064037,
- [P12] "Doppelgänger dark energy: modified gravity with non-universal couplings after GW170817" Luca Amendola, Dario Bettoni, Guillem Domènech & Adalto R. Gomes, arXiv:1803.06368, JCAP 1806 (2018) no.06, 029,
- [P11] "Hamiltonian approach to second order gauge invariant cosmological perturbations" Guillem Domènech & Misao Sasaki, arXiv:1709.09804, Phys.Rev. D97 (2018) no.2, 023521,

- [P10] "Thermal activation of thin-shells in anti-de Sitter black hole spacetime" Pisin Chen, Guillem Domènech, Misao Sasaki & Dong-han Yeom, arXiv:1704.04020, JHEP 1707 (2017) 134,
- [P9] "CMB Scale Dependent Non-Gaussianity from Massive Gravity during Inflation" Guillem Domènech, Takashi Hiramatsu, Chunshan Lin, Misao Sasaki, Maresuke Shiraishi & Yi Wang, arXiv:1701.05554, JCAP 1705 (2017) no.05, 034,
- [P8] "Strongly scale-dependent CMB dipolar asymmetry from super-curvature fluctuations" Christian Byrnes, Guillem Domènech, Misao Sasaki & Tomo Takahashi, arXiv:1610.02650, **JCAP 1612 (2016) no.12, 020**,
- [P7] "Consistency relation and inflaton field redefinition in the delta N formalism" Guillem Domenech, Jinn-Ouk Gong & Misao Sasaki, arXiv:1606.03343, Phys.Lett. B769 (2017) 413-417,
- [P6] "Inflationary Magnetogenesis with Broken Local U(1) Symmetry" Guillem Domènech, Chunshan Lin & Misao Sasaki, arXiv:1512.01108, EPL 115 (2016) no.1, 19001,
- [P5] "Stationary bubbles and their tunneling channels toward trivial geometry" Pisin Chen, Guillem Domènech, Misao Sasaki & Dong-han Yeom, arXiv:1512.00565, JCAP 1604 (2016) no.04, 013,
- [P4] "Derivative-dependent metric transformation and physical degrees of freedom" Guillem Domènech, Shinji Mukohyama, Ryo Namba, Atsushi Naruko, Rio Saitou & Yota Watanabe, arXiv:1507.05390, Phys.Rev. D92 (2015) no.8, 084027,
- [P3] "Cosmological disformal invariance" Guillem Domènech, Atsushi Naruko & Misao Sasaki, arXiv:1505.00174, JCAP 1510 (2015) no.10, 067,
- [P2] "Conformal Frame Dependence of Inflation" Guillem Domènech & Misao Sasaki, arXiv:1501.07699, JCAP 1504 (2015) no.04, 022) 134,
- [P1] "Fixing a Rigorous Formalism for the Accurate Analytic Derivation of Halo Properties" Enric Juan, Eduard Salvador-Solé, Guillem Domènech & Alberto Manrique, Mon.Not.Roy.Astron.Soc. 439 (2014) no.1, 719-724,
- [P0] "Halo Mass Definition and Multiplicity Function" Enric Juan, Eduard Salvador-Solé, Guillem Domènech & Alberto Manrique, Mon.Not.Roy.Astron.Soc. 439 (2014) no.3, 3156-3167,

### **Submitted**

[P22] "Neutrino masses, vacuum stability and quantum gravity prediction for the mass of the top quark" Guillem Domènech, Mark Goodsell & Christof Wetterich. arXiv:2008.04310.

## **Proceedings**

- [C3] "Inflationary Magnetogenesis with On-shell Local U(1) Symmetry" Guillem Domènech, Chunshan Lin & Misao Sasaki, J.Phys.Conf.Ser. 883 (2017) no.1, 012013
- [C2] "Conformal frames in cosmology" Guillem Domènech & Misao Sasaki, arXiv:1602.06332, Int.J.Mod.Phys. D25 (2016) no.13, 1645006,

[C1] "Stationary bubbles: information loss paradox?"

Guillem Domènech & Misao Sasaki,

arXiv:1602.04969, Everything about Gravity, pp. 572-577 (2017),

## **INTERNATIONAL TALKS:**

#### **Conferences:**

- 05/2020 Spring workshop in Gravity and Cosmology. Jagiellonian University, Poland.
- 05/2019 Spring workshop in Gravity and Cosmology. University of Warsaw, Poland.
- 07/2018 String Pheno 18. University of Warsaw, Poland.
- 02/2018 Gravity and Cosmology 2018. YITP, Japan.
- 08/2017 COSMO-17. APC, University Paris Diderot.
- 01/2017 Testing Gravity 2017. SFU, Canada.
- 10/2016 Gravitation and the Universe (HGU 2016). VAST, Vietnam. Workshop on General Relativity and Gravitation JGRG26, Osaka, Japan.
- 01/2016 Mini-Workshop on Cosmology. APCTP, Korea.
- 12/2015 2nd LeCosPA International Symposium: Everything about Gravity. LeCosPa, Taiwan. Workshop on General Relativity and Gravitation (JGRG25). YITP, Japan.
- 11/2015 2nd Mini-Workshop on Gravity and Cosmology. IAP, France.
- 12/2014 Workshop on General Relativity and Gravitation (JGRG24). IMPU, Japan.
- 10/2013 IX International Workshop, The Dark Side of the Universe. SISSA, Italy.

### **Invited seminars:**

- 07/2020 Padova university (webinar), Italy.
- 06/2020 McGill university (webinar), Canada.
- 01/2019 Johns Hopkins University, USA.
- 11/2018 ITP, Heidelberg, Germany.
- 10/2018 Warsaw University, Warsaw, Poland.
- 11/2017 ITP, Heidelberg, Germany.
- 09/2016 UPV-EHU, Bilbao, Spain.
  - University of Barcelona, Spain.
- 05/2016 NCTS, Hsinchu, Taiwan.
- 04/2016 LeCosPa, Taipei, Taiwan.
- 12/2015 University of Barcelona, Spain.
- 11/2015 IAP, Paris, France.
- 03/2015 APTCP, Pohang, Korea.

#### **Poster presentations:**

- 01/2017 Testing Gravity 2017. SFU, Vancouver, Canada.
- 06/2015 New Ideas Meet New Experimental Data. String Theory & Cosmology. Hong Kong

## Schools and workshops:

- 02/2016 School on Strings and Fields,
  - Yukawa Institute for Theoretical Physics, Kyoto University, Japan
- 08/2015 Summer School on Cosmology and Particle Astrophysics,
  - RESCEU APCosPA, Japan
- 05/2015 Molecular type Workshop: Black hole information loss paradox,
  - Yukawa Institute for Theoretical Physics, Kyoto University, Japan